Save the gorilla!
拯救大猩猩！
Protect tigers!
保护老虎！
Help the giant kangaroo rats!
帮助巨型袋鼠鼠！
You've probably heard the first two slogans but maybe not the last one.
你可能听过前两个口号，但可能没听过最后一个。
We're often keen to support the conservation of animals like gorillas and tigers but less sympathetic to creatures like rats.
我们常常热衷于支持大猩猩和老虎等动物的保护，但对老鼠之类的生物却不太同情。
Are our stereotypes affecting which animals we choose to protect?
我们的刻板印象是否影响了我们选择保护哪些动物？
Researchers have looked at the impact of 'warmth' – that's the perceived intentions, and 'competence' – the skill that different species appear to have.
研究人员研究了"温暖度"（即感知到的意图）和"能力"（不同物种表现出的技能）的影响。
It's suggested that people are very keen to protect 'companions', such as dogs or monkeys, who score highly in warmth and competence.
研究表明，人们非常热衷于保护"伙伴动物"，如狗或猴子，它们在温暖度和能力方面得分都很高。"
'Predators', such as tigers or bears, score highly in competence but low in warmth.
捕食者"，如老虎或熊，在能力方面得分高，但温暖度低。
They are said to inspire awe and fear, and this means that while some people are keen to protect them, others hunt them.
据说它们能激发敬畏和恐惧，这意味着虽然有些人热衷于保护它们，但另一些人却猎杀它们。
Animals seen as prey, like cows, rabbits, and pigs, generated more indifference, while people are prepared to actively harm those seen as low-warmth and low-competence 'pests', such as rats, mice, and fish.
被视为猎物的动物，如牛、兔子和猪，人们则对其更加漠不关心，而人们则准备主动伤害那些被视为低温暖度和低能力的"害虫"，如大老鼠、小老鼠和鱼类。
However, this might not be the full story.
然而，这可能并非全部事实。
National Geographic Magazine asked their readers which animals were the most important to save.
《国家地理》杂志曾询问读者哪些动物最重要需要保护。
Four of the top five fit the companion or predator types – elephants, tigers, whales and polar bears.
前五名中有四种符合伙伴动物或捕食者类型——大象、老虎、鲸鱼和北极熊。
But the most popular animal to save was the bee.
但最受欢迎的动物是蜜蜂。
It seems that apart from concerns around warmth and competence, people are aware how species can impact the wider ecosystem and value bees as pollinators.
除了对温暖度和能力的关注外，人们似乎还意识到物种如何影响更广泛的生态系统，并重视蜜蜂作为传粉者的价值。
According to some reports, 27,000 species are becoming extinct every year.
据报道，每年有2.7万个物种正在灭绝。
How do zoos and conservation projects decide which animals to support?
动物园和保护项目如何决定帮助哪些动物？
One factor is the importance of an animal to the wider ecosystem, but this can lead to some difficult choices.
一个因素是动物对更广泛生态系统的重要性，但这可能会带来一些艰难的选择。
Phys.org reports that in Australia, koalas are much less important to the ecosystem than some lesser-known animals such as woylies.
Phys.org报道称，在澳大利亚，考拉对生态系统的重要性远不如一些不太知名的动物，如沃伊利鼠。
However, they also suggest a solution to this issue.
然而，他们也提出了解决这一问题的办法。
To conserve cute animals, such as koalas, it's important to protect their entire habitat – and this can save a wide range of species.
为了保护考拉等可爱的动物，保护它们的整个栖息地非常重要——而这可以拯救多种物种。
It could be that many animals can be sheltered by koalas' cuteness.
也许很多动物可以因考拉的可爱而受到庇护。